blendercookie.com 2017-11-19

# Privacy Policy of cgcookie.com

## Data Controller and Owner

CG Cookie, Inc  
27 W. State Street, Ste B  
Geneva, IL

**Owner contact email:** support@cgcookie.com

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage Data, email address, first name, last name, province, state, country, ZIP/Postal code and website. 

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this Application.  
All Data requested by this Application is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services. In cases where this Application specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without any consequences on the availability or the functioning of the service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application serves the purpose of providing the service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

## The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, User database management, Heat mapping and session recording, Contacting the User, Remarketing and behavioral targeting, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Access to third party accounts, Displaying content from external platforms, Content performance and features testing (A/B testing), Advertising, Handling payments, Hosting and backend infrastructure and Managing contacts and sending messages. 

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  * ### Access to third party accounts

This type of service allows this Application to access Data from your account on a third party service and perform actions with it.  
These services are not activated automatically, but require explicit authorization by the User.

#### Stripe account access (Stripe Inc)

This service allows this Application to connect with the User's account on Stripe, provided by Stripe, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy)

  * ### Advertising

This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on this Application, possibly based on User interests.  
This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.  
Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Application. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.  
In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

#### DoubleClick for Publishers (Google Inc.)

DoubleClick for Publishers is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. that allows the Owner to run advertising campaigns in conjunction with external advertising networks that the Owner, unless otherwise specified in this document, has no direct relationship with. In order to opt out from being tracked by various advertising networks, Users may make use of [Youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). In order to understand Google's use of data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).  
This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of this Application and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.  
Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on: [www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en).

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/)

  * ### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

#### Google AdWords conversion tracking (Google Inc.)

Google AdWords conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google Inc. that connects data from the Google AdWords advertising network with actions performed on this Application.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### Segment (Segment Inc.)

Segment is an analytics service provided by Segment Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://segment.com/docs/legal/privacy/)

#### Hotjar Form Analysis & Conversion Funnels (Hotjar Ltd.)

Hotjar is an analytics service provided by Hotjar Ltd.  
Hotjar honors generic Do Not Track headers. This means your browser can tell its script not to collect any of your data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. Find Hotjar’s [opt-out information here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: Malta – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out)

#### Facebook Ads conversion tracking (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Ads conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects data from the Facebook advertising network with actions performed on this Application.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)

#### Twitter Ads conversion tracking (Twitter, Inc.)

Twitter Ads conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Twitter, Inc. that connects data from the Twitter advertising network with actions performed on this Application.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy)

  * ### Contacting the User

#### Mailing list or newsletter (This Application)

By registering on the mailing list or for the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning this Application. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to this Application or after making a purchase.

Personal Data collected: Cookies, country, email address, first name, last name, province, state, Usage Data, website and ZIP/Postal code. 

  * ### Content performance and features testing (A/B testing)

The services contained in this section allow the Owner to track and analyze the User response concerning web traffic or behavior regarding changes to the structure, text or any other component of this Application.

#### Optimizely (Optimizely, Inc.)

Optimizely is an A/B testing service provided by Optimizely, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.optimizely.com/privacy/)

  * ### Displaying content from external platforms

This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them.  
This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### YouTube video widget without cookies (Google Inc.)

YouTube is a video content visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.  
This widget is set up in a way that ensures that YouTube won't store information and cookies about Users on this Application unless they play the video.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### Gravatar (Automattic Inc.)

Gravatar is an image visualization service provided by Automattic Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.  
Please note that if Gravatar images are used for comment forms, the commenter's email address or parts of it may be sent to Gravatar - even if the commenter has not signed up for that service.

Personal Data collected: email address and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/)

#### Wistia widget (Wistia, Inc.)

Wistia is a video content visualization service provided by Wistia, Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://wistia.com/privacy)

#### Typekit (Adobe Systems Incorporated)

Typekit is a typeface visualization service provided by Adobe Systems Incorporated that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/typekit.html)

  * ### Handling payments

Payment processing services enable this Application to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, this Application shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.  
Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.

#### Stripe (Stripe Inc)

Stripe is a payment service provided by Stripe Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/terms/US)

  * ### Heat mapping and session recording

Heat Mapping services are used to display the areas of a page where Users most frequently move the mouse or click. This shows where the points of interest are. These services make it possible to monitor and analyze web traffic and keep track of User behavior.  
Some of these services may record sessions and make them available for later visual playback.

#### Hotjar Heat Maps & Recordings (Hotjar Ltd.)

Hotjar is a session recording and heat mapping service provided by Hotjar Ltd.  
Hotjar honors generic „Do Not Track” headers. This means the browser can tell its script not to collect any of the User's data. This is a setting that is available in all major browsers. Find Hotjar’s [opt-out information here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).

Personal Data collected: Cookies, Usage Data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: Malta – [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out)

  * ### Hosting and backend infrastructure

This type of service has the purpose of hosting data and files that enable this Application to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of this Application. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

#### Heroku (Heroku, Inc.)

Heroku is a hosting service provided by Heroku, Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.heroku.com/policy/privacy)

  * ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

This type of service allows interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Application.  
The interaction and information obtained through this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation)

#### Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter, Inc.)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy)

  * ### Managing contacts and sending messages

This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.  
These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

#### MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)

MailChimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.

Personal Data collected: email address. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

  * ### Remarketing and behavioral targeting

This type of service allows this Application and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Application by the User.  
This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.  
In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

#### AdWords Remarketing (Google Inc.)

AdWords Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

#### Facebook Custom Audience (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Custom Audience is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Facebook advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and email address. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/)

#### Facebook Remarketing (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Facebook advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/)

#### Twitter Remarketing (Twitter, Inc.)

Twitter Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Twitter, Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Twitter advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405)

#### Twitter Tailored Audiences (Twitter, Inc.)

Twitter Tailored Audiences is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Twitter, Inc. that connects the activity of this Application with the Twitter advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and email address. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405)

#### Perfect Audience (NowSpots, Inc.)

Perfect Audience is an advertising service provided by NowSpots, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.perfectaudience.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.perfectaudience.com/privacy/index.html#opt-out)

#### DoubleClick for Publishers Audience Extension (Google Inc.)

DoubleClick for Publishers Audience Extension is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that tracks the visitors of this Application and allows selected advertising partners to display targeted ads across the web to them.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb#display_optout)

  * ### User database management

This type of service allows the Owner to build user profiles by starting from an email address, a personal name, or other information that the User provides to this Application, as well as to track User activities through analytics features. This Personal Data may also be matched with publicly available information about the User (such as social networks' profiles) and used to build private profiles that the Owner can display and use for improving this Application.  
Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails based on specific actions performed on this Application.

#### Intercom (Intercom Inc.)

Intercom is a User database management service provided by Intercom Inc. Intercom can also be used as a medium for communications, either through email, or through messages within our product(s).

Personal Data collected: email address and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://docs.intercom.io/pricing-and-terms/privacy)

## Further information about Personal Data

  * ### Selling goods and services online

The Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services or to sell goods, including payment and possible delivery.  
The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may include the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by this Application depends on the payment system used.

  * ### The Service is not directed to children under the age of 13

Users declare themselves to be adult according to their applicable legislation. Minors may use this Application only with the assistance of a parent or guardian. Under no circumstance persons under the age of 13 may use this Application.

## Cookie Policy

This Application uses Cookies. To learn more and for a detailed cookie notice, you may consult the [Cookie Policy](https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/8157785/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy").

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities. 

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request. 

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address). 

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document. 

### The rights of Users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above. 

This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller remove the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users. 

### Information about this privacy policy

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on Iubenda's servers. 

###  Definitions and legal references 

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically from this Application (or third party services employed in this Application), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Application, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using this Application, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Subject

The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Application. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Application.

#### This Application

The hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected.

#### Cookies

Small piece of data stored in the User's device.

* * *

#### Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.

This privacy policy relates solely to this Application.
